Horace Gregory Papers
Horace Gregory Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Ruihley, Glenn Richard, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1936-1972; undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Russ, Elmo, 1935 (Box 11)
  - S, one folder (Box 11)
  - Sale, William Merritt, 1934 (Box 11)
  - Salomon, Isidore Lawrence, 1952; 1961 (Box 11)
  - Salzman, Jack, 1966; 1970,; undated (Box 11)
  - Salzmann, Jerome, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Sarah Lawrence College, 1959-1969; undated; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Sarton, May, 1943; 1952,; undated (Box 12)
  - The Saturday Review, 1953-1957 (Box 12)
  - Savell, Isabelle Keating, undated (Box 12)
  - Schacht, Marshall, 1937 (Box 12)
  - Scher, Jacob, 1936 (Box 12)
  - Schmitt, Gladys, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Schneider, Isidor, 1934-1937; undated (Box 12)
  - Schorer, Mark, 1959; 1961,; undated (Box 12)
  - Schubert, David (and Judith), 1936-1939; undated (Box 12)
  - Schwartz, Daniel Herbert, 1938 (Box 12)
  - Schwartz, Delmore, 1944; undated (Box 12)
  - Scott, Evelyn, 1933-1956; undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, 1933-1968; undated; miscellany; 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Sessions, Jack A., 1955 (Box 12)
  - Seward, William Ward, 1942; 1964 (Box 12)
  - Shelley Memorial Award, 1934-1935 (Box 12)
  - Sherwood, Robert E., 1945 (Box 12)
  - Shipley, Joseph T., 1942-1944 (Box 12)
  - Sichel, Pierre, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Sillen, Samuel, 1937-1938; undated (Box 12)
  - Silvette, Marcia, 1941-1946; undated (Box 12)
  - Siporin, Max, 1937 (Box 12)
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1944-1959; undated (Box 12)
  - Sitwell, Edith - A Celebration for Edith Sitwell, 1948 (Box 12)
  - Slade, Caroline, 1936 (Box 12)
  - Slate, Joseph Evans, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Slochower, Harry, 1933; 1937,; undated (Box 12)
  - Smith, Chard Powers - 1933, 1940; 1941,; undated (Box 12)
  - Smith, William Jay, 1956 (Box 12)
  - Spencer, Theodore, 1937; 1942,; 1944 (Box 12)
  - Spicer-Simpson, Theodore, 1952 (Box 12)
  - Stallman, Robert Wooster, 1949; 1955,; 1960 (Box 12)
  - Stein, Sol, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Steloff, Frances, 1962; 1967,; undated (Box 12)
  - Stepanchev, Stephen, 1938 (Box 12)
  - Stephan, Ruth, 1946; 1958 (Box 12)
  - Sternfeld, Frederick William, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Steuben Glass, 1961 (Box 12)
  - Stevens, Wallace, 1933 (Box 12)
  - Stevenson, Faber, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Stillman, Clara Gruening, 1938; 1947 (Box 12)
  - Stoddard, Hope, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Strachey, John, 1934 (Box 12)
  - Suckow, Ruth, 1946; undated (Box 12)
  - Sullivan, A. M., 1938 (Box 12)
  - Swados, Harvey, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Swan, Emma, 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Sweeney, James Johnson, 1959; 1961,; undated (Box 12)
  - Sweeney, John L., 1938-1967; undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - T, one folder (Box 13)
  - Taggard, Genevieve, 1942 (Box 13)
  - Talkington, Melinda, 1970 (Box 13)
  - Tambimuttu, T., See Poetry London - New York
  - Tamiris, undated (Box 13)
  - Tanasso, Elda, 1937 (Box 13)
  - Tate, Allen, 1932-1948 (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Harold, See Sarah Lawrence College
  - Tenon, Mathew, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Theobald, John, 1948; undated (Box 13)
  - Thirlwall, John C., 1954-1955 (Box 13)
  - Thompson, Dunstan, 1941-1945 (Box 13)
  - Thornton, M. B. (Margaret), 1956-1968; undated (Box 13)
  - The Tiger's Eye, 1948 (Box 13)
  - Triem, Eve, 1939 (Box 13)
  - Troy, William, 1933 (Box 13)
  - U, one folder (Box 13)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1955; 1959,; 1961 (Box 13)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1934-1971; undated; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Urzidil, Johannes, 1965 (Box 13)
  - V, one folder (Box 13)
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1937; 1945 (Box 13)
  - Vanguard Press, 1953-1958; undated (Box 13)
  - Varney, John, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Vaughan, George, 1937 (Box 13)
  - Viking Press, 1956-1969; undated (Box 13)
  - Viljoen, Helen Gill, 1935 (Box 13)
  - Villa, Jose Garcia, 1933; 1946-1959,; undated (Box 13)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1948-1959 (Box 13)
  - Vogel, Joseph, 1935-1940; undated (Box 13)
  - W, one folder (Box 13)
  - Wagner, Charles Abraham, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Wagner, Geoffrey, offprint (Box 13)
  - Waite, Marjorie Peabody, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Wallace, Michel, 1937 (Box 13)
  - Warren, Constance, 1944; undated (Box 13)
  - Webb, Jon, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Weber, Brom, 1962-1967; undated (Box 13)
  - Weber, Carl Jefferson, 1944 (Box 13)
  - Weiss, Theodore Russell, 1956; 1961-1967 (Box 13)
  - Weller, George Anthony, 1937 (Box 13)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1951 (Box 13)
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1964-1968 (Box 13)
  - Wheelwright, John, 1934-1935; undated (Box 13)
  - White, Robert Ogden, 1961; 1963,; undated (Box 13)
  - Whittemore, Reed, 1939; undated (Box 13)
  - Wilder, Isabel, 1958 (Box 13)
  - Wilder, Charlotte, 1933; undated (Box 13)
  - Wilkinson, Marguerite Ogden Bigelow, 1920; 1923,; undated (Box 13)
  - Williams, Gil, 1964; 1967,; undated (Box 14)
  - Williams, Oscar, undated (Box 14)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1934-1956 (Box 14)
  - Williams, William Carlos - "The Wedge", ms. (Box 14)
  - Williams, William Carlos, notes for a speech (Box 14)
  - Williams, William Carlos, poetry, miscellany (Box 14)
  - Wilson, Edmund, undated (Box 14)
  - Wilson, T. C., 1933-1947; undated; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Wilson, T. C., miscellany (Box 14)
  - Winters, Yvor, 1956 (Box 14)
  - Wisconsin Fellowship of Poets, 1960-1961 (Box 14)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1958-1968 (Box 14)
  - Wishart, Charles Frederick, 1951 (Box 14)
  - Worth, Kathryn, 1934-1937 (Box 14)
  - Wright, James Abell, 1966; 1969 (Box 14)
  - Wylie, Elinor, undated (Box 14)
  - X, one folder (Box 14)
  - Y, one folder (Box 14)
  - Yale University, 1953-1959; undated (Box 14)
  - Yellen, Samuel, 1945; 1953 (Box 14)
  - Young, Kathleen Tankersley, 1933-1934 (Box 14)
  - Z (Box 14)
  - Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1933-1963; undated; 6 folders (Box 14)
  - Zindel, Paul, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Zukovsky, Louis, 1937 (Box 14)
  - First names, unidentified (Box 14)
  - Printed material
    - Literary (Box 15)
    - Political - A-B (Box 15)
    - Political - C-L (Box 15)
    - Political - M-Z (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
- Writings
  - Horace Gregory - books (manuscripts)
    - Collected Poems, 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Cummings, E. E. A Selection of Poems, edited by H. Gregory, 9 folders (Box 16)
    - Dorothy Richardson: An Adventure in Self-Discovery, 12 folders (Box 16, 17)
    - The House on Jefferson Street, 27 folders (Box 17, 18, 19)
    - Love Poems of Ovid, 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Medusa in Gramercy Park, 1 folder (Box 19)
    - Poems 1930-1940, book with annotations, corrections, and additions (possibly used as a dummy for a later collection) (Box 19)
    - Poems of George Gordon, Lord Byron - Introduction by H. Gregory, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Spirit of Time and Place, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - The World of James McNeill Whistler, 5 folders (Box 20)
  - Marya Zaturenska - books (manuscripts)
    - Collected Poems, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - The Hidden Waterfall, 1 folder (Box 20)
    - Selected Poems of Christina Rossetti, edited, with an Introduction by M. Zaturenska; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Terraces of Light, 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Gregory-Zaturenska - books (manuscripts):
    - The Crystal Cabinet, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - A History of American Poetry 1900-1940, Foreword to reprint edition; 1 folder (Box 21)
    - The Silver Swan, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Horace Gregory - essays
    - "The Poem and the Muse", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "The Romantic Inventions of Vernon Lee", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "Second Thoughts on the Teaching of Contemporary Literatures" - Wisconsin Studies in Contemporary Literature, 1964 (Box 22)
    - "The Transcendentalism of Buffie Johnson", ms., with corrections; carbon of later ms. (Box 22)
    - Untitled, undated - (American culture), ms., with corrections (Box 22)
  - Marya Zaturenska - essays
    - "Emily Dickinson: Her Letter to the World", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "A Forgotten Masterpiece: 'Love's Cross Currents'", ms., with corrections (fragment) (Box 22)
    - "The Harp of Tara: Thomas Moore: a Fashionable Poet", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "John Donne: a Career of Passion and Poetry", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "The Life and Dream of William Morris", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "The Poet as Philosopher: Lord Herbert of Cherbury", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "Richard Lovelace 1618-1658: a Cavalier Poet: War Poets of the 17th Century", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "Robert Herrick: the Pagan Parson of Dean Prior", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "The Strange Victory of Sara Teasdale", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "Thomas Campion: the Poet as Musician", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
    - "A Victorian Modern: the Portrait Gallery of Robert Browning: with a note on Matthew Arnold", ms., with corrections (Box 22)
  - Marya Zaturenska - journals (notebooks)
    - 1932 (Box 22)
    - April 1938 (Box 22)
    - 1939? (Box 23)
    - from Oct. 1944 (Box 23)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 23)
    - Dec. 1958 - May 1960 (Box 23)
  - Horace Gregory - poetry
    - Untitled, undated - "White Protestant, pioneer American stock ...", typescript (Box 23)
  - Marya Zaturenska - poetry
    - "City Trees in April", holograph (Box 23)
    - "Michael Angelo Buonarroti: 1475-1564", holograph (Box 23)
    - Three Poems - Midland, 1925 (Box 23)
    - Worksheets and duplicates (Box 23)
  - Author unknown - poetry
    - "The Door in the Desert" (Box 23)
    - "For a Friend" (Box 23)
    - "The Meek shall disinherit the earth" (Box 23)
    - "Sunday Morning News: the Picture Section" (Box 23)
    - "they found him" (Box 23)
    - Untitled (3) (Box 23)
    - Italian translations of two poems by H. Gregory (Box 23)
  - Horace Gregory - reviews
    - "A One-Man Movement to Annihilate Mediocrity" The Letters of Wyndham Lewis, edited by W. K. Rose. The New York Times Book Review, Aug. 9, 1964
  - Marya Zaturenska - reviews
    - "The Patmores" Portrait of My Family, by Derek Patmore. The Nation, Dec. 4, 1935 (Box 23)
    - "The World of the Wordsworths as Dorothy Saw It" Journals of Dorothy Wordsworth, edited by E. De Selincourt. The New York Times Book Review, July 12, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Author unknown - reviews
    - Chorus for Survival, by Horace Gregory, draft of a review (Box 23)
  - Horace Gregory - speeches
    - "The Poem and the Muse", delivered at a Sarah Lawrence convocation (pasted inside Horizon issue pp. 30-43) (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous fragments (Box 23)
  - Notes, fragments (Box 23)
  - Horace Gregory - galleys
    - Collected Poems, 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Dorothy Richardson: An Adventure in Self-Discovery, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - The House on Jefferson Street, 1 folder (Box 24)
    - Medusa in Gramercy Park, 1 folder (Box 24)
    - Poems of George Gordon, Lord Byron, 1 folder (Box 24)
    - Spirit of Time and Place, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Portable Sherwood Anderson - Introduction, 1 folder (Box 25)
    - "The Art of Love" - translation of Ovid - Harper's Bazaar, 1 folder (Box 25)
  - Marya Zaturenska - galleys
    - Collected Poems, 1 folder (Box 25)
  - Gregory-Zaturenska - galleys
    - The Silver Swan, 1 folder (Box 25)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings - Horace Gregory
    - Reviews and articles about (Box 26)
  - Clippings - Marya Zaturenska
    - Reviews and articles about (Box 26)
  - Clippings - Gregory-Zaturenska
    - Reviews and articles about (Box 26)
  - Clippings (miscellaneous) (Box 26)
  - Financial material (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous items removed from M. Zaturenska's journal (Box 26)
  - Photograph of Harriton drawing of H. Gregory, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Photograph of Harriton drawing of M. Zaturenska, 1934 (Box 26)
  - Photographs (miscellaneous) (Box 26)
  - Printed material
    - Direction, 1938; v. 1, no. 5 (Box 26)
    - The Left, spring 1931; v. 1, no. 1 (Box 26)
    - miscellaneous (Box 26)
  - Programs from Italian productions and various other mementos from European trip, 2 folders (Box 26)